SKILLS Java cybersecurity Spring Framework Hibernate JPA SQL and PL/SQL Javascript Restful web services Micro web services **JDBC** HTML **CSS** Reactis Redux ElasticSearch Git **Design Patterns JDeveloper** English Spanish French .lira Excel

Luis Guillermo Rossano Esquivel

Software Developer

+52(833)4926348

Jesus Urueta 203, Col Los Mangos, Cd Madero, Tamaulipas luis.grossano29@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/luisrossano-2a2613199

OBJECTIVE

Dedicated software developer who is passionate and has five years of experience in building and testing back-end side applications. Posses experience with programming languages, particularly skilled in Java and Spring framework. Committed to contribute with the organization growth.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Client: BlueYonder, Monterrey, Mexico

January 2023 - Present

June 2021 - May 2022

Role: Consulting Software Engineer

Development, fixing and testing of projects of clients, giving updates and follow ups of any changes with specifications of error or new feature needed.

Responsibilities:

- Apply agile methodology to project process.
- Testing and debugging any errors found on current projects of supply chain and make reports of status.
- Check XML workflow in development of processes.
- Develop of webservices and API in order to enhance supply chain.

Tech Stack: Reactjs, Axios, Reduxjs, ElasticSearch, Jda, Weblogic, SQL, Java 1.8, XML, Restful web services, Git, Jira, Agile.

Client: Tata Consultancy Services, Guadalajara,

Mexico

Role: Java Developer/Systems Engineer

Development of services for a clients, apply best practices and improve upon project to reduce any existing bugs in client application.

Responsibilities:

- Analyze projects structure with client, apply agile methodology.
- Develop User interface using React(JavaScript library).
- Apply and use Kafka for streaming pipeline and monitoring data of the consuming api when users interact with the application.
- Develop Restful web services check any possible errors follow the project all the way thru release into production.
- Applying Spring security for api protection layer protocol, in other words spring security is applied to web services to give roles and privileges to users.

Tech Stack: Java 1.8, Kafka, Springboot, Spring MVC, XML, Spring Security, React(JavaScript library), Restful web services, Git, Agile.

Client: Totalplay S.A De C.V, Mexico City

June 2019 - July 2020

Role: Java Developer

Worked as a software developer managing restful web services updating projects, adding new features of optimization for services such as communication and internet services.

Responsibilities:

 Create Java REST and SOAP web services for multiple projects that required updates by the client. Worked along with my team to create web application that helps the company keep track of tools for installing telecommunications services, for the development of this web application, restful services, MVC approach were used along with the use of Oracle SQL data to keep track of vehicles, and using Firebase

for keeping track record of users.

- Wrote, check and update Oracle PL/SQL scripts for multiple process in web services.
- Worked with encryption for app URL and json entries

Tech Stack: Java 1.8, OOP, Spring Boot, Spring, XML, Google Firebase platform, Tomcat Postman, PL/SQL, Hibernate, Oracle SQL, Git, SOA, JDeveloper, agile.

Client: Ernst & Young, Mexico City

July 2018 - May 2019

Role: RPA Developer/Java Developer

Worked as both RPA and Java Developer on couple of projects that involved managing the processes for web interfaces and create automated process to execute the jobs.

Responsibilities:

- Develop automated systems to speed up billing process using Spring framework along with RPA Automation anywhere tool.
- Ticket system project maintenance, improvement(updating) of processes in Restful web services, DAO and creation of stored procedures using Oracle 11g SQL.
- Develop and check automated process using RPA tools such as Automation Anywhere, BluePrism, UIPath.
- Check and verify any corrections need for clients invoice portal automated process, if they are able to respond properly to object detection and generate reports if otherwise for immediate correction or update.

Tech Stack: Java 1.8, Springboot, Spring MVC, DAO, Singleton, OOP, XML, Oracle SQL, EXCEL, RPA, Automation Anywhere, Blueprism, UIPath.

Client: INDIMEIN S.A De C.V, Mexico City

January 2018 - June 2018

Role: Java Developer

Responsibilities:

- Migration of warehouse system, where it went from desktop to a web version, input and output modules, provider catalog and access history of employees.

Tech Stack: Java 1.8, Spring, XML, Hibernate, Restful web services, Oracle 11g SQL.

Client: Aksi herramientas, Mexico city

July 2017 - December 2017

Role: Java Developer

Worked in microservices project to update and improve management of the sales system and kept registry of every product sold

Responsibilities:

- Involved in the redesign and, development and implementation of a sales system web application .
- Partial management of the front end of the sales systems development by using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Develop restful web services to get information from the user, products being sold and store data of transactions into database.
- System functionality tests.

Tech Stack: Java, Springboot, web services (REST and SOAP), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Oracle 11g SQL.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas Rio Grande Valley, Edinburg, TX, USA Bachelor of Science in Computer Science August 2013 - May 2017

OWASP training LinkedIn

